Jai Hind friends, today's video is going to be
very informative
and is going to be on a very important topic. It is
estimated that Muslims ask a lot of questions on this topic
that insurance is not getting passed here
and for that, if it has to be passed, then
which category of license should we have. So, let
me give you this information that there are categories in it
and I am going to tell you later
which category of license
you should have. If
you watch this video from beginning to end, then no
doubt you will get the answer to all your questions
in this video, this is a guarantee.
First of all, you people should like this video. Those who
forget later, then
like this video right now. If you are going to
get some valuable information in this video, then you should also
share this video and subscribe to this channel and press the
bell icon
so that you keep getting such informative videos of RTO or
transport sector. Press the
bell icon for sure, for
90% of the people who take the policy  We
take insurance, why do we take it? The
reason is that it is mandatory, if
you buy a car in the beginning, you will have to take insurance, be it for
one year, two years or five years. At some places, you
get offers etc., so
people take it for two, four or five years, but
they take it, okay, then you should take insurance
and every person should hold the insurance policy,
this only harms you
because you take the
financial responsibility of your car from the third party,
so listen to this carefully, but
despite this, you know that
despite having insurance, in accidental cases, many
people, if I talk to you, then its
ratio has reached almost 40%, those people are
not even able to pass the insurance,
holding the policy is a different thing, but if
God forbid, there is a bad accident somewhere
or someone meets with an accident there, then
if you have insurance, whether it is your own
or
comprehensive or any third party insurance, then you are
not able to get it passed, its
data is very big, why it is not
possible, I will give you information in this.
Yes, many people fall into this category.
In this pursuit, they
even pay thousands of rupees to brokers to get their insurance passed, but
still their insurance is not passed. They do
not get the money. They keep
roaming from one office to another.
So why does this happen? See, the
biggest reason for claims not getting passed is that
in a survey, it was found that
many people in India do not know
which category of license is required to drive which vehicle.
Many people do
not have a driving license at all. You understand,
and many people who have a
driving license, the
particular license required in it is
accident prone, then the license of that category should be there only
then the insurance will be passed. It is
not that you are
driving a four-wheeler, an accident happened
with a four-wheeler or some accident happened due to
mishap,
which license did you get from a four-
wheeler? Now you will say that I have a
license, but still
why is my insurance not getting passed? So the
reason is that you do
not have the required category of license.  If you are
driving a four wheeler then you must have a four
wheeler ticket license and that
too a valid license it is
not that it is a learner license or
else let me tell you one more thing that learner license is
not valid at all, no
insurance will be passed with it, it is
valid only for 6 months and you do
not even have the freedom to drive alone with it, so
sister please remove this thing from your mind, first of all
you should get a married license which is a
driving license and the proper
license which is the license for driving a vehicle,
you understand, many
people who are diesel manufacturers do
not know the categories, so let me tell
you that under the Motor Vehicle Act
1988 I am going to
tell you the categories of license, if you are driving a four wheeler,
if you have a two wheeler then
you must have a private category license, I understand you
transport, you must have a private category
license, if you have this license then only
your insurance will be passed if
in future any wrong activity happens there, let's say an
accident happens, a
student happens, anything happens, then there is
insurance in accidental case  The pass will be a two
wheeler
vehicle which is for
transport, it should be
long and at the same time if you are
driving a high category vehicle and there is an accident with it, then
in such a case you must have a trans
license or ANS trans which is
a part of heavy license, that license
is mandatory if you do not have this license
then the insurance will not pass no matter
what you do if
you have an accident somewhere with a three wheeler or you
drive then it is mandatory for me to have a three and three wheeler
license, you are the operator of loader, extra
weight, JCB, all these
vehicles and so you should
also have a responsibility that it is
mandatory to have a proper license to drive all the vehicles in India, so if you drive a
JCB, loader etc. in a cutting vehicle then you must have an
ldrxcb license, only then your
license is valid, like you will also be saved from challan,
this list that I told you,
you will also be saved from challan, if an accident happens then you will be
passed for that also and you
We will be safe
because if you have all the documents, then
friends, in India most of the insurance claims are not passed due to this reason,
many people get trapped in this and get entangled, so
I have told you the thing so that
you can be careful, if you still have any doubt or question, then
you can join us
in our YouTube comment section here
or to give advice or suggestion, to
talk,
join us on Instagram Twitter,
you will get the answer to your question,
join the Telegram group,
thank you very much for watching the video till here,
but if you have not subscribed to the channel yet, then do it,
share this video and also like it,
thank you, Jai Hind Vande Mataram